I've been using the iron bull unleash
lifting straps over the past couple
weeks and I love the 5mm neoprene
padding and the high quality nylon build
but favorite thing here is that my grip
strength has been a complete non-factor
during my workouts there's a lot of
lifting straps on the market but these
are some of my personal favorites so
let's dive into a full
review
what's up everybody it's Jake back in
the barbing garage gym and for today's
video I'm going to be breaking down the
iron bull unleash lifting straps I'm
going to talk about a lot of stuff in
this video but specifically we're going
to talk about some money the pros of
using lifting straps and then of course
who should or maybe you know shouldn't
purchase these now before I do all of
that I got to let yall know that we've
reviewed a whole lot of lifting straps
on barb. comom and we went ahead and
made a best list of all of our top picks
so if you want to check that out all you
got to do is search barbin best lifting
straps it's going to pull right up for
you you can find out for yourself which
ones we like the
[Music]
best okay so first off what is a lifting
strap okay so lifting straps are
completely different from wrist wraps
all right so a wrist wrap goes around
your wrist and that's going to add you
more stability within that joint right
there and that's really nice you know if
you have an injury but also as you're
going to lift some heavy weight just
kind of stabilizes your wrist right
there so with a lifting strap that's
designed to go you know around a barbell
a dumbbell lat pull down attachment use
it for rows maybe even pull-ups really
whatever it is it's going to take your
grip strength and your forearms
everything completely out of the
equation that way you're able to focus
on your target muscles and then
essentially lift heavier weight so you
know it's a very good thing you never
want to be limited by your grip strength
and that's where these really come into
play now I don't think there's any cons
with these specific lifting straps but
once again I really do like this 5mm
neoprene padding it feels good on your
wrist you know there's not going to be
any pinching or you know any digging
into your wrist whatsoever I like that
and also just the nylon build in general
is really high quality and I think these
are going to last you I'd say at least a
year right right around that time frame
and then these are also going to cost
you 22 bucks now they're more expensive
than a lot of other lifting straps that
are on the market but by about five
bucks Maybe six bucks or so so it's
really not that bad and the fact that
you are getting that neoprene padding
and that high quality build I think
makes it worth the
[Music]
money so once again the ironbull unleash
lifting straps are going to run you
right around $22 I personally think
that's pretty solid however as I
mentioned you know there's a lot of
other options that are around five six
bucks cheaper online ironbo actually has
some cheaper ones as well they have a
pair that are going to cost you about
$16 but they also have their figure
eights those are going to run you around
30 bucks and the reason those are more
expensive is because overall it's just a
whole lot easier to get positioned
rather than you know taking the time to
wrap you know the strap around your
barbell dumbbell or whatever it is but
like I said 22 bucks at the end of the
day for the quality of these it's a
pretty solid price
[Music]
tag
all right so you know once again you do
have your 5mm neoprene padding right
here this is great you know not every
single lifting strap has that I
personally like that I'm sure some
people you know will disagree with me
but having that up on your skin is
really nice you know it's not going to
pinch you you kind of get uncomfortable
even just kind of you know rub against
your skin I like that so and you also
have this really high quality you know
nylon the stitching is there's no phrase
at all like I said I've been using these
for a while they basically look brand
new okay so when it comes to actually
using these I would recommend using your
non-dominant hand first and what you
want to do is basically just run this
through I am going to use my dominant
hand right now though so basically just
go ahead you know put this I'm going go
and make that a little tighter put your
hand in make this tight that's what I
like to do at least and then what you
want to do is take this and wrap it
around you I'm using a dumbbell you can
use like I said barbell pull-up bar
whatever just basically wrap this around
and then once it gets kind of right here
you want to twist it with your hand
twist keep twisting basically until it
won't anymore and this strap gets really
close to the bar or you know dumbbell
handle whatever all right so we're
basically as far as it'll go and that's
it and you can kind of see you know my
forearm still involved but not as much
as it would be if I you know didn't have
this and this really comes in handy like
I said whether whether you're doing you
know shrugs you're doing rdls you're
doing rows with a barbell pull Downs
anything it doesn't matter having that
is just going to pretty much completely
eliminate your grip strength and allow
you to lift heavier weight now unless
you want to save around five bucks or so
with a different pair of lifting straps
or maybe there's a specific brain you're
loyal to I don't think there's any
reason to not purchase these lifting
straps I do think there's many reasons
to buy them specifically you know once
again talking about grip strength if
you're somebody who struggles with grip
strength you know especially you know
deing your pull movements maybe you're
doing some rdls shrugs deadlifts really
whatever it is where that grip is really
you know a limiting factor this is any
lifting strap in general is going to be
you know great for you they're going to
completely take that away which allows
you to focus on your target muscles lift
heavier weight which essentially leads
to more gains in the long run and that's
something that we all want
[Music]
all right that's all I got for y'all
today on the iron bull unleash lifting
straps the neoprene padding feels really
good on your wrist they're super high
quality and then they're simply just
going to allow you to lift heavier
weight thanks for watching everybody I
hope this video was really helpful I was
able to tell you everything you need to
know about these lifting straps
stay posted for my next video but for
now head over to bar.com so we have a
full written article about these straps
all you got to do is search barbend Iron
bull unleash lifting straps review it's
going to pull right up for you you can
go over every single thing we talked
about here today I'll catch you on next
time